Guide to the Walter and Martha Leuba Papers, 1735-1988 SC.1988.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Correspondence, II.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1.
    - Porteous, Bob & Ellen, 1965-1975 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Prager, Ruth, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Ritchie, Ward, 1976-1977 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Rowland, Mary Gwynne (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Sanders, Charles Richard, 1955-1985 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Schlesinger, Rosa, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Schuman, Anna (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Siegel, Eli, 1925-1964 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Siegel, Eli, 1933-1969 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Smith, Dory A., 1926 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Stanwyck, A.L., 1956-1960 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Starrett, Agnes, 1955-1972 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Stoneburner, Tony, 1969-1971 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Sussman, Naomi (re: Haniel Long), 1976 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Tarleton, Fiswoode, 1923-1926 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Various (Announcements), 1935-1974 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Various (re: Crusade), 1977 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Various (re: Genealogy), circa 1973 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Various (Holiday Cards), 1944-1973 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Various (Illegible or No Last Name), 1926-1979 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Various, 1932-1936 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Various by Author A-F, 1926-1977 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Various by Author G-M, 1924-1972 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Various by Author N-Z, 1899-1976 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Volkmann, Louise ("Großmutter"), 1910-1919 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Wallach, Esther ("Mother"), 1932-1933 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Weinstein, Irving, 1939-1987 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Wilderich, Tom, 1949-1951 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Wittenborn, George, 1960-1962 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Wolf, Robert, 1924-1926 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Zuccala, George, 1924 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - Professional Correspondence, 1915-1986; 3.
    Subseries contains correspondence between Leuba and various editors, publishers, and organizations. Correspondence is grouped alphabetically by last name or corporate name.
    - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1951-1966 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, 1970-1979 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - The Critic, 1946-1947 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Davis & Warde, Inc., 1970-1983 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - The Echo, 1925-1929 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - E.P. Dutton & Co., Inc., 1966 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Filby, Bill, 1965-1977 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Fritts, Norman, 1924 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Gehenna Press, 1961-1963 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Harper's Magazine, 1947 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Hastings House, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Holloway, Mark, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - International Poetry Forum, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Johansen, Gunnar and Lorraine, 1960-1963 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Lawrence, George H.M., 1965 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Lee, Lawrence, 1966, 1975 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Lhombreaud, Roger, 1952, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Long, Anton, 1965-1967 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - The Macmillan Company, 1934-1952 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Mason, John, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - McIntosh & Otis, Inc., 1936 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Morley, Christopher, 1932-1933 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Morris, Henry, 1918-1919 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Palms Poems, 1923-1973 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Pears, Tom, 1970-1976 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Pittsburgh Bibliophiles, 1964-1973 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Pittsburgh History & Landmarks Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Rees, Richard, 1930 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Silver, Rollo, 1960-1981 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1950-1958 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Stauffacher, Jack Werner, 1974, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1971-1977 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1977-1986 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Various, 1915-1976 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Various Authors, 1924-1975 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Voices, 1924-1928 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - The Wanderer, 1924-1926 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Wilson, Adrian, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence with Mildred Leuba, 1926-circa 1930; 3.
    Subseries consists of two bound scrapbook volumes of correspondence and other materials. Volume I primarily consists of handwritten letters, photographs, original poetry, and other material, such as telegrams, hotel receipts, and other miscellaneous items. Volume II also contains correspondence from and about Mildred, including a considerable correspondence with Eli Siegel. Both volumes are digitized and presented online in this finding aid.
    - M.L. Vol. I, 1926-1929 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - M.L. Vol. II, circa 1930 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Walter Leuba, 1921-1974; 4.
    Subseries consists of correspondence written by Walter Leuba to various recipients. The letters are arranged chronologically with undated items at the end.
    - Leuba, Walter to Various, 1921-1974 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- ALS and TLS, 1735-1986; III.
  Series consists of Leuba's collection of Autograph and Typescript Letters, Signed (ALS and TLS) from notable writers, artists, and other public figures. Series includes items dating from 1735 to 1986, although many items are undated. Series is divided into 3 subseries: (1) Letters by Book Illustrators and Printers; (2) Letters by Writers; and (3) Letters by Others. Leuba's lists of items within his collection are included at the beginning of subseries 1 and 2. These lists include many, though not all of the items in this series.
  - Letters by Book Illustrators and Printers, 1818-1986; 1911-1986; 1.
    Subseries contains Leuba's collection of Autograph and Typescript Letters, Signed (ALS and TLS), from 1818 to 1986. Letters are addressed to various recipients, including some to Walter Leuba. A list in Leuba's hand, "Letters, ALS and TLS, of book illustrators and printers" appears at the beginning of the subseries and lists many, though not all, of the ALS and TLS in the subseries.
    - Letters, ALS and TLS, of book illustrators & printers (list) (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Abbe, Elfried, 1956-1974 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Angel – Ardizzone, 1942, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Armitage, Edward, 1873 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Austein, John, 1938-1940 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Baily – Bennett, 1837, 1960-1961 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Blumenthal, Joseph, 1946-1977 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Bone, Muirhead, 1926-1937, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Bostock – Callcott, 1818, 1955-1958 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Carter, Will, 1965-1967, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - [Chambers, J] (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Charlot – Coughlin, 1932-1966 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Crane, Walter, 1889-1905 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Craxton, John, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Creswick, Thomas (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Cruikshank, George, 1844-1877 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Daglish, Eric, 1925 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - DePol, John, 1959-1978 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Dalziel – Escher, 1844-1879, 1916, 1964-1966 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Evans, Henry, 1963-1977 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Farleigh, John, 1948-1957 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Fielding – Gill, 1829, 1922-1960 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Glasser, Howard, 1970-1977 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Glick, William, 1961-1973 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Gourdie, Tom, 1966-1979 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - Gaudier-Brzeska, Henri, December 12 [1912?] (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Hanna, Boyd, 1971-1981 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - Jones, David, 1925-1929 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Kauffer – Kent, 1942-1962 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Kittredge, William, 1929-1933 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Koch – Lamb, 1930-1966 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Leighton, Clare, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Low, Joseph, 1962-1968 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Lucas – Maynard, 1924-1966 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Nama, George, 1963-1977 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Nash, John, circa 1965 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Nicholson – Pierce, 1920-1956 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - Odle, Alan, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Peterson, Norton, circa 1971-1974 (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Ransom, Will, 1945-1948 (Box 28, Folder 40)
    - Reed- Reimer, 1946-1949 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Rice, Anne Estelle, 1911-1914 (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Ross, Thomas, 1973-1977 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Rutherston - Steinhardt, 1921-1957 (Box 28, Folder 44)
    - Stone, Reynolds & Janet, 1946-1957 (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Wall - Zapf, 1915-1964 (Box 28, Folder 46)
  - Letters by Writers, 1735-1974; 1901-1974; 2.
    Subseries contains Leuba's collection of Autograph and Typescript Letters, Signed (ALS and TLS) from 1735 to 1974. Letters are addressed to various people, including some to Walter Leuba. Bulk are in English; some French. A list in Leuba's hand, "Letters of Writers" appears at the beginning of the subseries and lists many, though not all of the ALS and TLS in the subseries.
    - Letters of Writers (list) (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Abercrombie, Lascelles, 1934 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Anthony, Edward (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Armstrong, Martin, 1920-1929 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Auden, Thomas, 1905 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Agassiz – Ashby-Sterry, 1795-1899 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Bailey, B., 1835 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Ball, Edward (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Besant, Walter, 1896 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Bates, Herbert Ernest, 1929-1931 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Binyon, Lawrence, 1914-1952 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Barham – Barrie, 1895, 1924-1926 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Baxter – Beranger, 1833-1874, 1913-1927 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Birrell – Burke, 1884-1900, 1913-1932 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Carlyle, Thomas, 1846-1872 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Chateaubriant [Chateaubriand, François-René, vicomte de] (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Colum, Padraic, 1931 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Cooper, Courtney Ryley, 1922 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Cruden, Robert Peirce, 1826 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Cayley – Craig, 1824-1866, 1904-1929 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Crothers – Dobson, 1800-1850, 1897-1955 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Douglas – Egan, 1790-1830, 1883, 1919-1932 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Erskine, John, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Fern, Alan, 1965-1967 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - Fothergill, Jessie, 1890 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Fuller, Henry B, circa 1920 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - Fitzgerald – France, 1886-1914 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Froude, J[ames] A[nthony], circa 1877 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Furnivall – Goldring, 1872, 1902-1932 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Gosse, Edmund, 1869-1921 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Graham – Grey, 1888-1898 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Guedella, Philip (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Guilbert – Housman, 1840, 1890-1923 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Hughes, Richard, 1924 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Howells – Hume, 1842-1886, 1905 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - Hutton, Richard Holt, 1872 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Huxley, J. – Lamartine, 1857-1859, 1905-1926 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - Lang, A., 1897-1914 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - Lecky, W.H., 1872 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Leslie, Shane, 1920-1931 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Lewes, G.H., Mrs. [George Eliot], 1874 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Locker-Lampson – Macauley, 1823-1894, 1920-1968 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Massingham – Moultou, 1849-1894, 1920-1931 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Munden – Powys, 1852-1900, 1912-1947 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Quiller-Couch, Arthur ["Q"], 1912-1935 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Priestley – Repplier, 1909-1939 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Raleigh, Walter Alexander, 1904, 1915 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - Read, Herbert, 1919-1929 (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - Reynolds, Stephen, 1909-1913 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - Rhys – Roche, 1895-1920 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - Rogers, Samuel (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Ruskin – Sainte-Beuve (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Saintsbury, George, 1886-1929, 1945, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Shaw – Smith, 1908-1965 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Smith, Sydney, 1825-1843, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Sotheby – Thornbury, 1860-1930 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Roberts, Charles G.D., 1893 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Robertson, Philip Wilfred, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Traill, H.D., 1892-1899 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Trollope – Yeats, 1820-1836, 1886-1937 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Wallace, Alfred Russel, 1907 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Walpole, Hugh, 1928 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Wheatly, C. [Charles], 1735 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Winter, William, 1901 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Yates, Edmund, 1857 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Letters by Others, circa 1804-1978; 3.
    Subseries contains Leuba's collection of Autograph and Typed Letters, Signed (ALS and TLS) from historical and political figures, as well as letters with illegible signatures or unknown profession. Most letters are undated, but range from circa 1804 to 1978. Letters include examples from a Crimean War correspondent, British nobility, and a small group of materials by and about British naturalists, among others. In addition to signed letters, subseries 3 also contains related materials, such as a signed 1807 promissory note between radical publisher and MP, William Cobbett, and Richard Bagshaw. Also, includes one folder of facsimile plates of letters and other items related to Robert Burns, Admiral Rodney, and Sir Nicholas and Nathaniel Bacon.
    - Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, Earl of, 1886 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Bandinel, [Bulkeley] [Librarian of the Bodleian] (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Bentham, Jeremy (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Bignold, Samuel, Mayor of Norwich, 1834 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Blessington, [Marguerite, Countess of], to Captain Marryat, circa 1840 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Botfield, Beriah, 1842-1854 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - British Naturalists - Asa Gray, Roger Lispey, and Alfred Wallace, 1879, 1907, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Cambridge, Augusta, [The Duchess of], 1822 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Collins, J.C., 1893 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Gray, Asa, 1879 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Kensington Palace, 1849 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Magee, James M. (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Spencer, [Charles Robert Spencer, Earl], 1887 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Sykes, Mark Masterman, circa 1804 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Promissory note – W[illia]m Cobbett to Rich[ard] Bagshaw, Newsman, 1807 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Facsimiles of 18th century manuscript materials - Sir Nicholas and Sir Nathaniel Bacon; Robert Burns; and Admiral Rodney (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Illegible and/or Unknown, 1742, 1802-1889, 1929 (Box 30, Folder 32)
- Inventories and Notes, 1820-1977; 1902-1977; IV.
  Series contains notes and inventories related to a variety of subjects and in a variety of formats, including typed and handwritten reading notes, bound journals listing books read, notes and register pages related to Leuba exhibits, and thematic groups of index cards or notecards (e.g. grouped by Leuba by author or artist, lists of first names, and other topics.) Names or subject terms are provided from the first and last pages of binders and noteboxes, where available. Binder pages have been left in the order in which they were bindered, boxed, or fastened (some fastenings have been removed for preservation purposes). Bulk of material is undated, dates are listed where available. Oversize materials have been separated for storage purposes and are listed at the end of this Series.
  - Miscellaneous bibliographic records and lists (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Catalog list - "Autograph Letters, Etc. – Miscellaneous" (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Catalog of artists, presses, and publishers, binder 1: Ackermann to Copeland & Day (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Catalog of artists, presses, and publishers, binder 2: Curwen Press to Hanson (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Catalog of artists, presses, and publishers, binder 3: Harbor Press to Ness (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Catalog of artists, presses, and publishers, binder 4: Nordquist to Seymour (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Catalog of artists, presses, and publishers, binder 5: Shephard to Zingg (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Catalog of bibliographic records (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
    Folder contents include "Calligraphy & The Alphabet," "Printers & Printing," artist names, author names.
  - Prints catalog: Binder 1 (of 3) [Abbe, Elfriede – Gross, Anthony] (Box 32, Volume 1)
  - Prints catalog: Binder 2 (of 3) [Hainard, Robert – Othon-Friesz, E.] (Box 32, Volume 2)
  - Prints catalog: Binder 3 (of 3) [Parker, Agnes Miller – Zortea, F] (Box 32, Volume 3)
  - Catalog of Japanese Prints (Box 32, Volume 4)
  - Catalog of artists and presses (Box 32, Volume 5)
  - Notes and Citations on Saintsbury and others: Binders 1 and 2 (Box 32, Volume 6-7)
  - Prices recorded by W.L. for the press books in case L-2, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Subject Terms/ Names Catalog Binders (Box 33, Volume 1-2)
  - Catalog Binder "[Gar]nett, [Gre]enhood, [?]ng, [Le]uba" (Box 33, Volume 3)
  - Catalog Binder [Jackson, Holbrook - Merimee, Prosper ] (Box 33, Volume 4)
  - Catalog Binder "George Saintsbury (1)" (Box 33, Volume 5)
  - Catalog Binder "George Saintsbury (2)" (Box 33, Volume 6)
  - Catalog Binder "Flowers, etc." [Adrian, M/Ferguson - Hylander, C/Johnston, E.F] (Box 34, Volume 1)
  - Catalog Binder "Bach, Carlyle, Greece, Rome" (Box 34, Volume 2)
  - Catalog Binder "Eliot, Guiney, Pound, Smith" (Box 34, Volume 3)
  - Catalog Binder [Cimino, H] (Box 34, Volume 4)
  - Notebox of Catalog Pages [Adams, A - Shakespeare] (Box 34, Carton 1)
  - Notebox of Catalog Pages [Authors] (Box 34, Carton 2)
  - Notebox of Catalog Pages [A-B / Abbot - Basile] (Box 34, Carton 3)
  - Catalog Notepages [G - P] (Box 35, Other 1)
  - Catalog Notepages [Bennet, Richard - Darwin, Bernard] (Box 35, Other 2)
  - Catalog Notepages [Benham, W. - Clarendon Press] (Box 35, Other 3)
  - Catalog Notepages [Anderson, Edgar - Jones, P] (Box 35, Other 4)
  - Catalog Notepages [Darwin, Bernard - g, RMY] (Box 35, Other 5)
  - Loose Catalog Notepages (Box 35, Other 6-9)
  - Loose Catalog Notepages - List of Poems by WL/PS (Box 35, Other 10)
  - Alphabetically Ordered Index Cards (Box 36)
  - Alphabetically Ordered Index Cards (Box 37)
  - Loose Index Cards (Box 38)
  - Notebooks - Miscellaneous Presses (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks - Porter Garnett, Curwen Press / Helen Gentry, Oxford, Misc Sets, and Untitled (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Memobooks (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Notecards (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Leuba Print Exhibit Guide and Guest Register (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Leuba Exhibit Notes (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Woodblock and Wood Engraving Print Techniques, Catalog of Print Collection (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Catalog Binder Be-By [Beaumont, Francis – Byron, Lord] (Box 40, Volume 1)
  - Catalog Binder C [Cabell, James Branch – Curwen, Henry] (Box 40, Volume 2)
  - Catalog Binder D [Daiches, David – Dyer, John] (Box 40, Volume 3)
  - Catalog Binder E-F [Earle, John – Fung Yu-Lan] (Box 40, Other 1)
  - Catalog Binder G [Gale, Zona – Gwynn, Frederick L.] (Box 40, Volume 4)
  - Binder H [Haberly, Loyd – Hyde, Walter Woodburn] (Box 40, Other 2)
  - Binder I-K [Ibn Jubayr – Kyd, Thomas] (Box 40, Volume 5)
  - Binder L [La Fontaine – Lynd, Robert] (Box 41, Other 1)
  - Binder M [Mabie, Hamilton Wright - Musee] (Box 41, Volume 1)
  - Binder N-R [Nabokov, Vladimir – Putz, Alfred] (Box 41, Volume 2)
  - Binder [Quaife, Milo Milton – Ryder, Arthur William] (Box 41, Volume 3)
  - Binder S-Sha [Sackville-West, V. – Seymour, Ralph Fletcher] (Box 41, Volume 4)
  - Binder Shand [Shand, P. Morton – Synge, John M.] (Box 41, Volume 5)
  - Binder T-Z [Tabb, John Banister – Vulliamy, C.E.] (Box 41, Volume 6)
  - Binder W [Waddell, Helen – Zweig, Stefan] (Box 41, Volume 7)
  - Misc. notes and clippings, circa 1943 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Reading-Reference Notes I (Box 42, Folder 2-3)
  - Reading-Reference Notes II (Box 42, Folder 4-6)
  - Women's names (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Index cards: first names (Box 43, Other 1-10)
  - First name notes and clippings (Box 43, Folder 1)
    Folder contents includes poem by Wilder Bentley, 1972.
  - Reading notes and index cards (Box 43, Folder 1-3)
  - Books Read: 1931, circa 1931 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Memo book - reading notes (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Notebook - reading notes, 1946-1947 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Notes and spiral-bound notebook (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Notes, clippings, correspondence, 1917-1976 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Clippings and Notes, 1968-1977 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Reading notes, ephemera (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Reading Notes, Correspondence, Ephemera, circa 1929 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Notes (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Notes, 1949-1957 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Notes - The Tempest excerpts (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Notes - Quotes and Prayers (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Notes, Transcriptions, Bibliographies (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Notes and Clippings (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Notes, Diary Pages, Correspondence, 1936-1974 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Literary Magazine Clippings (Box 45, Folder 8-9)
  - Notes, Correspondence, Autographs, and Clippings, 1820, 1917, 1933-1970 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Notes, clippings, correspondence, diary, 1926-1971 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Clippings from Times Literary Supplement, 1951-1965 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Related Material, 1902-1965 (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Case File Notes, circa 1937-1947 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Case File Notes, Transcriptions, and Correspondence, 1935-1948 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Case File Transcriptions (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Profile of Helen Clay Frick, 1939 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Oversize prints, sketches, clippings, notes, Bach score (Box 64, Folder 1)
- Personal Papers, 1868-1988; 1914-1988; V.
  Series contains personal papers related to Walter and Martha Leuba, including diary pages, genealogy notes, diplomas, and certificates. Series is arranged into 3 subseries: (1) Diaries and Journals, (2) Biography and Genealogy, and (3) Official Documents. Subseries 3 contains oversize materials; oversize items were separated for storage purposes and are listed at the end of the subseries. Leuba's personal papers, especially diary and journal pages, often refer to his book collecting and research activities; for related material, see also Leuba's reading notes in Series IV (Inventories and Notes).
  - Diaries and Journals, 1928-1988; 1.
    Subseries consists of personal diary and journals by Walter Leuba, as well as some journal material for Martha Leuba. Includes wall and appointment calendars with detailed personal entries, especially between 1984-1987. Entries describe family life, social work, reflections on prints and literature, and major events such as WWII or the Kennedy assassination. Folders are arranged chronologically; undated materials are found at the end of the subseries.
    - Journal pages typed, 1917-1933 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - "Diary 1928," Bound Typescript (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - "Diary 1931-1932," Bound Typescript (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Journal Pages and Notes typed, circa 1963 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Journal Pages, circa 1963 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Calendars, 1972-1979, 1984-1987 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Days of a Year, 1975 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Martha Leuba Journal, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Martha Leuba Journal (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Pocket Memo Books and Diaries, 1928-1956 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Biography and Genealogy, 1868-1980; 1917-1980; 2.
    Subseries includes material collected by Walter Leuba from and about family members. Includes biographical material written by Leuba and others. Also includes genealogy materials, such as birth and marriage certificates from family members, as well as war ration books and passenger lists from 1926 transatlantic crossing and other materials.
    - Family Records and Photographs, 1921-1925 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Family Records and Genealogy, Notes, and Correspondence, 1925-1976 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Family Records, Misc Documents, 1868-1976 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Personal and Family Notes, 1917-1942, 1970 (Box 48, Folder 5)